<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devstack on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/devstack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devstack on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/devstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Keystone with Cassandra Database in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>Using Cassandra as backing database for OpenStack Keystone was our solution to multi-region deployment problem of OpenStack cloud. This blog post is not to discuss the problem. We are talking about how to have a development environment to play around with Keystone working with a dev Cassandra deployment.
&amp;ldquo;Just run this script and you&#39;re all set!&amp;rdquo; I&#39;ve put together all commands into a script which can be found here:
https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rushiagr/keystone-cassandra/master/keystone-cassandra.sh  If you have a fresh Ubuntu VM, just copy this script into that machine and execute it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevStack behind proxy</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</guid>
      <description>I have now seen some people struggling to get DevStack working behind proxy. Some, thinking it is a bug in DevStack, have actually posted patches for it too! Here, I&#39;ll tell you the simple way to get stack.sh complete succesfully from behind a proxy.
By default, devstack will clone from the &amp;lsquo;actual&amp;rsquo; OpenStack git repositories, residing at git://git.openstack.org. Some people might face a problem with it, as DevStack uses git protocol to clone the repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack in an hour with DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you found out a cool new technology &amp;ldquo;OpenStack&amp;rdquo; and want to try it real quick? Or probably you are hired in a company for your Python skills and now you are supposed to work on OpenStack in the shortest possible time? Fear not, it is not that hard to get started. &lt;a href=&#34;http://devstack.org&#34;&gt;DevStack&lt;/a&gt; is your friend-in-need. No, don&#39;t click that hyperlink just yet :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Screens in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog article explains handling screens within OpenStack running as a DevStack setup. Some useful generic screen commands are also provided at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>