<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ubuntu on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ubuntu on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:59:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Tmux copy paste - Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:59:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Copying from a Tmux session is something every Tmux user struggled with once. I&#39;m listing out all the stuff I learnt in this blog.
I tested everything on Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr, which runs Tmux version 1.8 (I have a few commands included for Tmux version 2+ also) To check your Tmux version, run tmux -V. If you have a Mac, see here.
Know about copy buffers When you do a CTRL`+`c, the stuff you copy is stored in your computer&#39;s buffer, called &amp;lsquo;clipboard&amp;rsquo; from where you can paste anywhere by doing a CTRL+&#39;v&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet installation from modules</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/14/puppet-installation-from-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/14/puppet-installation-from-modules/</guid>
      <description>A quick example of how to use Puppet to install and manage MySQL. We&#39;ll download required Puppet modules from their git repositories.
Again, everything is tried on Ubuntu (14.04).
Make sure hostname -f shows your FQDN. Then install puppet
sudo apt-get install puppet  We&#39;ll use git submodules to manage different git repositories. But first, create our own repository
mkdir puppet-mysql cd puppet-mysql git init  Install Puppet modules stdlib and mysql into directory modules as git submodules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iSCSI administration on Ubuntu - Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/iscsi-administration-on-ubuntu-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/iscsi-administration-on-ubuntu-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>This post get&#39;s you started with iSCSI administration on an Ubuntu machine. Although I have used Ubuntu Trusty (14.04) version, it should work with Precise (12.04) too, with the latest packages.
Prerequisites Make sure you have atleast a little idea of what these terms mean: iSCSI, LUN, IQN, initiator, target and portal. Google and wikipedia are your friends.
A quick summary: There are two parts of iSCSI communication - initiator and target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Puppet - Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/12/open-source-puppet-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/12/open-source-puppet-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to be your quickest guide to get started with Puppet. We&#39;ll be using the open source version of Puppet. An hour of spare time and two Ubuntu machines (physical or virtual doesn&#39;t matter) is all that is needed.
Quick Introduction Lets say you want to install and run apache server on one of the machines in your lab. On another, you want to create a new user. On a third machine, you want to install MySQL, and allow access to this machine only from the first server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack in an hour with DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you found out a cool new technology &amp;ldquo;OpenStack&amp;rdquo; and want to try it real quick? Or probably you are hired in a company for your Python skills and now you are supposed to work on OpenStack in the shortest possible time? Fear not, it is not that hard to get started. &lt;a href=&#34;http://devstack.org&#34;&gt;DevStack&lt;/a&gt; is your friend-in-need. No, don&#39;t click that hyperlink just yet :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Databases are so important, yet almost all the time I need to work with it, I find that I have already forgotten all the syntax! So here I am writing down a quick cheat sheet to get me up and running when I&#39;m waking up from slumber. I hope this will help atleast one other guy on this planet.
I use mostly Ubuntu, so some of the commands might be Ubuntu specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing around with Cinder multi-backend</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Grizzly release, Cinder got equipped with another major feature &amp;ndash; multi-backends
with filter scheduler. So now you can have more than one storage boxes for block storage
and manage them with one Cinder deployment. Here, I&#39;m going to test it out using our
favourite method &amp;ndash; trying it out on DevStack!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start: Linux Logical Volume Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/14/quick-start-linux-logical-volume-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/14/quick-start-linux-logical-volume-manager/</guid>
      <description>While installing the latest Ubuntu OS on your computer, you will see that you can install the OS using LVM (Logical Volume Manager) utility. Ever wonder what is it? LVM (Logical Volume Manager) is that fantastic utility for storage administration. It provide the users with abilities which were not possible with raw disks. The storage is now &amp;lsquo;virtualized&amp;rsquo;. You can now easily create, move and extend volumes (for now, think of it as disk partitions) without bothering about data corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenID plugin for MediaWiki</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/12/installing-openid-plugin-for-mediawiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/12/installing-openid-plugin-for-mediawiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about setting up your wiki such that their users access the wiki
only via an OpenID provider login (e.g. Google or Facebook login). This post assumes
MediaWiki is already installed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>