<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mysql on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/mysql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mysql on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Better way to view MySQL tables</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/12/12/better-way-to-view-mysql-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/12/12/better-way-to-view-mysql-tables/</guid>
      <description>The problem You are trying to print a MySQL table with a large number of columns, with SELECT * command. You type SELECT * FROM mysql.user LIMIT 1, and your terminal becomes this. If you wanted to view more than one row, you&#39;re in a trouble :)
The solution Run MySQL with this option:
mysql --pager=&amp;quot;less --chop-long-lines --quit-if-one-screen --no-init&#39;  This will make your table display only the rows it can in the current screen, something like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet installation from modules</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/14/puppet-installation-from-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/14/puppet-installation-from-modules/</guid>
      <description>A quick example of how to use Puppet to install and manage MySQL. We&#39;ll download required Puppet modules from their git repositories.
Again, everything is tried on Ubuntu (14.04).
Make sure hostname -f shows your FQDN. Then install puppet
sudo apt-get install puppet  We&#39;ll use git submodules to manage different git repositories. But first, create our own repository
mkdir puppet-mysql cd puppet-mysql git init  Install Puppet modules stdlib and mysql into directory modules as git submodules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Databases are so important, yet almost all the time I need to work with it, I find that I have already forgotten all the syntax! So here I am writing down a quick cheat sheet to get me up and running when I&#39;m waking up from slumber. I hope this will help atleast one other guy on this planet.
I use mostly Ubuntu, so some of the commands might be Ubuntu specific.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>