<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DevStack behind proxy</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</guid>
      <description>I have now seen some people struggling to get DevStack working behind proxy. Some, thinking it is a bug in DevStack, have actually posted patches for it too! Here, I&#39;ll tell you the simple way to get stack.sh complete succesfully from behind a proxy.
By default, devstack will clone from the &amp;lsquo;actual&amp;rsquo; OpenStack git repositories, residing at git://git.openstack.org. Some people might face a problem with it, as DevStack uses git protocol to clone the repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting QCOW2 images</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/02/qcow2-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/02/qcow2-mount/</guid>
      <description>Isn&#39;t it fun that even before you start a VM out of an image, you can add files to that image, see and edit the directory and file structure of that VM?
I wanted to boot a VM out of a disk-image, but how will I know out of the 256 available IPs for that VM, which one actually got assigned? I tried vnc console, but the connection was terribly flaky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Puppet - Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/12/open-source-puppet-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/12/open-source-puppet-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to be your quickest guide to get started with Puppet. We&#39;ll be using the open source version of Puppet. An hour of spare time and two Ubuntu machines (physical or virtual doesn&#39;t matter) is all that is needed.
Quick Introduction Lets say you want to install and run apache server on one of the machines in your lab. On another, you want to create a new user. On a third machine, you want to install MySQL, and allow access to this machine only from the first server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack in an hour with DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/04/03/openstack-in-an-hour-with-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you found out a cool new technology &amp;ldquo;OpenStack&amp;rdquo; and want to try it real quick? Or probably you are hired in a company for your Python skills and now you are supposed to work on OpenStack in the shortest possible time? Fear not, it is not that hard to get started. &lt;a href=&#34;http://devstack.org&#34;&gt;DevStack&lt;/a&gt; is your friend-in-need. No, don&#39;t click that hyperlink just yet :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/03/31/mysql-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Databases are so important, yet almost all the time I need to work with it, I find that I have already forgotten all the syntax! So here I am writing down a quick cheat sheet to get me up and running when I&#39;m waking up from slumber. I hope this will help atleast one other guy on this planet.
I use mostly Ubuntu, so some of the commands might be Ubuntu specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing around with Cinder multi-backend</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Grizzly release, Cinder got equipped with another major feature &amp;ndash; multi-backends
with filter scheduler. So now you can have more than one storage boxes for block storage
and manage them with one Cinder deployment. Here, I&#39;m going to test it out using our
favourite method &amp;ndash; trying it out on DevStack!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start: Linux Logical Volume Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/14/quick-start-linux-logical-volume-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/14/quick-start-linux-logical-volume-manager/</guid>
      <description>While installing the latest Ubuntu OS on your computer, you will see that you can install the OS using LVM (Logical Volume Manager) utility. Ever wonder what is it? LVM (Logical Volume Manager) is that fantastic utility for storage administration. It provide the users with abilities which were not possible with raw disks. The storage is now &amp;lsquo;virtualized&amp;rsquo;. You can now easily create, move and extend volumes (for now, think of it as disk partitions) without bothering about data corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenID plugin for MediaWiki</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/12/installing-openid-plugin-for-mediawiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/12/installing-openid-plugin-for-mediawiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about setting up your wiki such that their users access the wiki
only via an OpenID provider login (e.g. Google or Facebook login). This post assumes
MediaWiki is already installed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Screens in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog article explains handling screens within OpenStack running as a DevStack setup. Some useful generic screen commands are also provided at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Tempest quick start with DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/20/openstack-tempest-quick-start-with-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/20/openstack-tempest-quick-start-with-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE(April 2014): Now when you set up DevStack, Tempest is automatically set up for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quick start guide explains setting up Tempest with a DevStack environment
for Grizzly release. Most of the information here is taken from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joinfu.com/2012/03/testing-essex-rc1-with-devstack-and-tempest/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the only difference being this blog post is more recent, and is based on Grizzly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git(hub) Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/19/github-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/19/github-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am posting my github cheat sheet here. I started writing it as soon as I started
learning Github and Git. So, some of the content here can appear quite naive.
I will try to keep this blog post as updated as I can, and if you find any
suggestion, please comment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just for a reference of commands. This post will be a bad way to learn
how git works. A basic understanding of git is assumed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>