<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 17:59:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Engineer Beginner Mistakes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/10/11/python-engineer-beginner-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 17:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/10/11/python-engineer-beginner-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>I am writing Python code since 5 years, and I have worked with around 5-6 entry-level Python programmers. There is a pattern I can see in their programming practices. My hope is by reading this article there will be lesser such mistakes.
I have worked on OpenStack for over three years, which is written in Python and has a very high code quality, so I feel I am qualified enough to write this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A different approach to AWS CLI</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/02/better-aws-command-line-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/02/better-aws-command-line-interface/</guid>
      <description>For a user of Amazon Web Services, quickly viewing a dashboard of all resources is not straightforward. If using a web browser, the session won&#39;t persist for more than a day and one will have to re-authenticate every day. If using AWS CLI, then he/she might not remember the exact command (was it describe-key-pair or describe-keypair or describe-keypairs?) but even if they do, the output is a not-so-readable JSON. For viewing virtual machines, you might not want to see hundreds of lines of detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick JustDial scraper</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/14/quick-justdial-scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/14/quick-justdial-scraper/</guid>
      <description>So my friend asked me to scrape data from JustDial and give it to him in an excel sheet. I thought let&#39;s give it a try. He needed name of firm, address and phone number of any JustDial URL he wants to scrape. After effectively around 4 hours of work, the below script was created.
Note that the script is dirty. You need to edit the jd_url to search any other URL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>