<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build VM Images using Diskimage-builder</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/02/build-vm-image-using-diskimage-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/02/build-vm-image-using-diskimage-builder/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack has this nice tool diskimage-builderto create virtual machine images without the need of a cloud. These vm images can then be uploaded to cloud (e.g. in Glance for OpenStack cloud), and they become immediately usable. You can also create VMs in virtualbox from these images (though I don&#39;t remember exact steps to make the image work with VirtualBox. Do let me know if you get the VM working with VirtualBox/Vagrant)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Keystone with Cassandra Database in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>Using Cassandra as backing database for OpenStack Keystone was our solution to multi-region deployment problem of OpenStack cloud. This blog post is not to discuss the problem. We are talking about how to have a development environment to play around with Keystone working with a dev Cassandra deployment.
&amp;ldquo;Just run this script and you&#39;re all set!&amp;rdquo; I&#39;ve put together all commands into a script which can be found here:
https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rushiagr/keystone-cassandra/master/keystone-cassandra.sh  If you have a fresh Ubuntu VM, just copy this script into that machine and execute it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache mod_wsgi parallelization notes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/07/24/apache-mod_wsgi-parallelization-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/07/24/apache-mod_wsgi-parallelization-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is my notes on &amp;lsquo;Processes and Threading&amp;rsquo; doc by the author of mod_wsgi module of Apache. This blog post just serves as a &amp;lsquo;quick refresher&amp;rsquo;, and is only useful if you have read the original document but it&#39;s been too long since you read it :)
Apache with mod_wsgi A Python application can run with multiple processes as well as multiple threads with mod_wsgi.
Prefork multiprocessing module Apache creates multiple processes, and each request is handled by one process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker quick start notes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/06/07/docker-quick-start-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/06/07/docker-quick-start-notes/</guid>
      <description>Update *: Blog updated to use latest way to install docker.  After reading about docker and containers, I thought let&#39;s try them out. Here are my notes. Obviously all of them are taken from Internet. Maybe this collection here will help someone start with docker faster than spending time searching all over the internet.
It assumes your base OS is Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr (when was the last time you saw the codename spelled &amp;lsquo;Trusty Tahr&amp;rsquo; and not &amp;lsquo;Trusty&amp;rsquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iSCSI administration on Ubuntu - Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/iscsi-administration-on-ubuntu-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/iscsi-administration-on-ubuntu-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>This post get&#39;s you started with iSCSI administration on an Ubuntu machine. Although I have used Ubuntu Trusty (14.04) version, it should work with Precise (12.04) too, with the latest packages.
Prerequisites Make sure you have atleast a little idea of what these terms mean: iSCSI, LUN, IQN, initiator, target and portal. Google and wikipedia are your friends.
A quick summary: There are two parts of iSCSI communication - initiator and target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Unit Testing Nuggets</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/openstack-unit-testing-nuggets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/09/05/openstack-unit-testing-nuggets/</guid>
      <description>A small post about little things I found out while running unit tests in OpenStack.
Unit-testing setup Everybody knows ./run_tests.sh is used to run the unit tests of an OpenStack project. But, you require to install dependencies before doing it. And installing dependencies might not always succeed. So make sure you install these packages before running pip install -r requirements.txt:
sudo apt-get install build-essential libssl-dev libffi-dev \ python-dev libxslt1-dev libpq-dev python-mysqldb \ libmysqlclient-dev libvirt-dev  Atleast cinder and nova dependencies will get installed properly after this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon EC2 API with OpenStack - Developer Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/09/amazon-ec2-api-with-openstack-developer-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/09/amazon-ec2-api-with-openstack-developer-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack has support for EC2 API, that is, you can fire Amazon&#39;s API against an OpenStack cloud and it will still work. This article gets you started with using them locally against DevStack. It is more of a starter guide to a novice.
Fire a DevStack with it&#39;s default settings. See this post for more information on it.
git clone http://github.com/openstack-dev/devstack cd devstack/ ./stack.sh  Source openrc
source openrc  View all EC2 credentials available for the current user (here, demo user in demo tenant)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevStack behind proxy</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/05/devstack-behind-proxy/</guid>
      <description>I have now seen some people struggling to get DevStack working behind proxy. Some, thinking it is a bug in DevStack, have actually posted patches for it too! Here, I&#39;ll tell you the simple way to get stack.sh complete succesfully from behind a proxy.
By default, devstack will clone from the &amp;lsquo;actual&amp;rsquo; OpenStack git repositories, residing at git://git.openstack.org. Some people might face a problem with it, as DevStack uses git protocol to clone the repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting QCOW2 images</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/02/qcow2-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/08/02/qcow2-mount/</guid>
      <description>Isn&#39;t it fun that even before you start a VM out of an image, you can add files to that image, see and edit the directory and file structure of that VM?
I wanted to boot a VM out of a disk-image, but how will I know out of the 256 available IPs for that VM, which one actually got assigned? I tried vnc console, but the connection was terribly flaky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing around with Cinder multi-backend</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2014/01/16/playing-around-with-cinder-backend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Grizzly release, Cinder got equipped with another major feature &amp;ndash; multi-backends
with filter scheduler. So now you can have more than one storage boxes for block storage
and manage them with one Cinder deployment. Here, I&#39;m going to test it out using our
favourite method &amp;ndash; trying it out on DevStack!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Screens in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/06/05/linux-screens-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog article explains handling screens within OpenStack running as a DevStack setup. Some useful generic screen commands are also provided at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinder on DevStack - Quick Start</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/05/27/cinder-on-devstack-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/05/27/cinder-on-devstack-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post covers all the important commands for OpenStack Cinder - The block storage project.
Although this guide is written based on DevStack, it will work with actual deployment of OpenStack
cloud also (except the DevStack/Linux specific bits).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Tempest quick start with DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/20/openstack-tempest-quick-start-with-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2013/03/20/openstack-tempest-quick-start-with-devstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE(April 2014): Now when you set up DevStack, Tempest is automatically set up for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quick start guide explains setting up Tempest with a DevStack environment
for Grizzly release. Most of the information here is taken from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joinfu.com/2012/03/testing-essex-rc1-with-devstack-and-tempest/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the only difference being this blog post is more recent, and is based on Grizzly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>