<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 19:05:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra server in 10 minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/12/08/cassandra-server-in-10-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 19:05:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/12/08/cassandra-server-in-10-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Want to quickly find out how a Cassandra server feels? In this blog post, we&#39;ll create a single-node Cassandra cluster on an Ubuntu Xenial (16.04) system. It&#39;s not really a &amp;lsquo;cluster&amp;rsquo;, but you can access the Cassandra shell cqlsh and try out all of its commands. Since we are just looking for a quick start, we&#39;re installing one of the latest Cassandra versions &amp;ndash; version 3.7. Even more, the steps here are totally scriptable, so you can just blindly paste the lines and it&#39;ll work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Engineer Beginner Mistakes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/10/11/python-engineer-beginner-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 17:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/10/11/python-engineer-beginner-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>I am writing Python code since 5 years, and I have worked with around 5-6 entry-level Python programmers. There is a pattern I can see in their programming practices. My hope is by reading this article there will be lesser such mistakes.
I have worked on OpenStack for over three years, which is written in Python and has a very high code quality, so I feel I am qualified enough to write this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes in 30 minutes with minikube on Mac</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/08/16/kubernetes-in-30-minutes-with-minikube-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 17:03:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/08/16/kubernetes-in-30-minutes-with-minikube-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Below are steps to create an express setup of Kubernetes on your Mac for quick use.
Minikube is a small setup by Kubernetes guys, which will spawn a virtual machine and have a tiny (but fully functional) Kubernetes cluster inside the VM. kubectl (pronounced &amp;lsquo;kube (like &amp;lsquo;tube&amp;rsquo;) control`) is the command line client you&#39;ll use to connect to the Kubernetes cluster (which runs inside the VM created by minikube, in case you forgot :) )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Vagrant Synced folders on Ubuntu Xenial guest work on Mac</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/07/20/vagrant-shared-folder-in-mac-xenial-guest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 23:18:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/07/20/vagrant-shared-folder-in-mac-xenial-guest/</guid>
      <description>Today I installed latest Vagrant, version 1.8.5. I was waiting for a newer release because 1.8.1 and previous versions don&#39;t work well with host-only networks for Ubuntu Xenial (16.04) guests on my Mac running El Capitan. But I faced another issue now:
mount: unknown filesystem type &#39;vboxsf&#39;  This is while specifying a synced folder in my Vagrantfile with this line:
config.vm.synced_folder(&amp;quot;/Users/apple/src/myutils&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;/home/ubuntu/myutils&amp;quot;)  where myutils is where I keep all my commandline shortcuts, tricks, and other shortcut-ish stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You dont need Vim swap files. And how to get rid of them</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/17/you-dont-need-vim-swap-files-and-how-to-get-rid-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 11:18:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/17/you-dont-need-vim-swap-files-and-how-to-get-rid-of-them/</guid>
      <description>Estimated reading time: 5 minutes.
Almost all IDEs today have &amp;lsquo;autosave&amp;rsquo; feature. That is, you don&#39;t need to explicitly save a file. The file is automatically saved as you type, so that even if your computer crashes, you don&#39;t lose data. This makes me wonder why Vim&#39;s default behavior is of using swap files. Swap files are annoying. I&#39;ve seen all Vim developers, including me, struggle with swap files at one point in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Tmux copy paste - Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:59:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Copying from a Tmux session is something every Tmux user struggled with once. I&#39;m listing out all the stuff I learnt in this blog.
I tested everything on Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr, which runs Tmux version 1.8 (I have a few commands included for Tmux version 2+ also) To check your Tmux version, run tmux -V. If you have a Mac, see here.
Know about copy buffers When you do a CTRL`+`c, the stuff you copy is stored in your computer&#39;s buffer, called &amp;lsquo;clipboard&amp;rsquo; from where you can paste anywhere by doing a CTRL+&#39;v&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Tmux copy paste</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:58:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting/</guid>
      <description>Copying from a Tmux session is something every Tmux user struggled with once. I&#39;m listing out all the stuff I learnt in this blog.
I tested everything on Mac OS X El Capitan. For Ubuntu/Linux guide, see here. Mac OS X El Capitan runs Tmux version 2.1. To check your Tmux version, run tmux -V.
Know about your terminal The default terminal which comes with Mac is pretty limiting. Instead of listing the limitations (and workarounds around it), I&#39;ll just say that before you proceed, please install iTerm 2 and start using that immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Pelican to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/24/moving-from-pelican-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 21:19:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/24/moving-from-pelican-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a better theme for my blog which is based on Pelican static site generator in Python, but then I happened to look at this blog written in Hugo - a Go counterpart of Pelican. The thing which caught my eye was the posts page, which is exactly how I wanted my first page to be. I&#39;ve always wanted something like Paul Graham&#39;s essays page, but couldn&#39;t find anything close to it until I found this site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>