<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 11:18:27 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>You dont need Vim swap files. And how to get rid of them</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/17/you-dont-need-vim-swap-files-and-how-to-get-rid-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 11:18:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/17/you-dont-need-vim-swap-files-and-how-to-get-rid-of-them/</guid>
      <description>Estimated reading time: 5 minutes.
Almost all IDEs today have &amp;lsquo;autosave&amp;rsquo; feature. That is, you don&#39;t need to explicitly save a file. The file is automatically saved as you type, so that even if your computer crashes, you don&#39;t lose data. This makes me wonder why Vim&#39;s default behavior is of using swap files. Swap files are annoying. I&#39;ve seen all Vim developers, including me, struggle with swap files at one point in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Tmux copy paste - Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:59:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Copying from a Tmux session is something every Tmux user struggled with once. I&#39;m listing out all the stuff I learnt in this blog.
I tested everything on Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr, which runs Tmux version 1.8 (I have a few commands included for Tmux version 2+ also) To check your Tmux version, run tmux -V. If you have a Mac, see here.
Know about copy buffers When you do a CTRL`+`c, the stuff you copy is stored in your computer&#39;s buffer, called &amp;lsquo;clipboard&amp;rsquo; from where you can paste anywhere by doing a CTRL+&#39;v&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Tmux copy paste</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 10:58:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/06/16/everything-you-need-to-know-about-tmux-copy-pasting/</guid>
      <description>Copying from a Tmux session is something every Tmux user struggled with once. I&#39;m listing out all the stuff I learnt in this blog.
I tested everything on Mac OS X El Capitan. For Ubuntu/Linux guide, see here. Mac OS X El Capitan runs Tmux version 2.1. To check your Tmux version, run tmux -V.
Know about your terminal The default terminal which comes with Mac is pretty limiting. Instead of listing the limitations (and workarounds around it), I&#39;ll just say that before you proceed, please install iTerm 2 and start using that immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmux session shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/10/tmux-session-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/01/10/tmux-session-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Tmux is awesome. But the session management commands are way too long for my liking. Listing all sessions is tmux list-sessions, attaching to a session mysession is tmux attach -t mysession, etc.
So I created a few functions and aliases, which can be found here.
The general idea is, all commands start with mx, which is basically a shortcut for &amp;lsquo;tMuX&amp;rsquo;. So mxl is to &amp;lsquo;l&#39;ist tmux sessions, mxa is to &amp;lsquo;a&#39;ttach to a tmux session, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>