<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cassandra on rushiagr</title>
    <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/cassandra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cassandra on rushiagr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rushi Agrawal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 19:05:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rushiagr.com/tags/cassandra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra server in 10 minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/12/08/cassandra-server-in-10-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 19:05:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2016/12/08/cassandra-server-in-10-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Want to quickly find out how a Cassandra server feels? In this blog post, we&#39;ll create a single-node Cassandra cluster on an Ubuntu Xenial (16.04) system. It&#39;s not really a &amp;lsquo;cluster&amp;rsquo;, but you can access the Cassandra shell cqlsh and try out all of its commands. Since we are just looking for a quick start, we&#39;re installing one of the latest Cassandra versions &amp;ndash; version 3.7. Even more, the steps here are totally scriptable, so you can just blindly paste the lines and it&#39;ll work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Keystone with Cassandra Database in DevStack</title>
      <link>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rushiagr.com/blog/2015/09/10/openstack-keystone-with-cassandra-database-in-devstack/</guid>
      <description>Using Cassandra as backing database for OpenStack Keystone was our solution to multi-region deployment problem of OpenStack cloud. This blog post is not to discuss the problem. We are talking about how to have a development environment to play around with Keystone working with a dev Cassandra deployment.
&amp;ldquo;Just run this script and you&#39;re all set!&amp;rdquo; I&#39;ve put together all commands into a script which can be found here:
https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rushiagr/keystone-cassandra/master/keystone-cassandra.sh  If you have a fresh Ubuntu VM, just copy this script into that machine and execute it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>